Matvey Volodin, Mobile software Test Engineer

Aqtobe, Kazakhstan • qa.volodin@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/matveyvolodin/ • github.com/matveyvolodin.

SUMMARY

Software Test Engineer with a comprehensive QA theory basis, solid understanding of software development life cycle (SDLC) and some experience in testing under Windows and Android environment. Additionally, I have a background in law, which provides me with the ability to understand legal language, attention to detail, and analytical skills. These skills sometimes aid me in developing testing documentation or working with requirements.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Moscow, Russia, May 2014 – Jul 2022 – Self-employed Lawyer,

- For the eight years preceding my relocation, I worked as a self-employed lawyer specializing in civil cases. Throughout my law practice, I conducted approximately 10 court sessions and held 10 personal consultations each month.
- Managing my own legal practice demanded a high level of personal responsibility, where I independently handled a wide range of tasks, from client interactions to case management.

Moscow Bar Association "Defense", Moscow, Russia, 2012-2014 – Lawyer's Assistant

EDUCATION

Functional software testing course, on-line, Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

Some of my testing documentation developed during my studies you can check here: github.com/matveyvolodin.

University of Industry and finance, civil law faculty, Moscow, Sept 2008 - Aug 2012 - Lawyer

SKILLS & OTHER

Hard skills:

Knowledge of software testing theory basics; Ability to design check lists and test cases, prepare test data for testing, manually execute tests and prepare test summary reports; Knowledge of project management systems like Jira, YouTrack, Qase, and Confluence documentation tool; Experience in API testing using Postman and SoapUI; Experience in mobile applications testing using Android studio; Experience in data testing using MySQL and MongoDB; Experience using sniffers for testing: Charlesproxy and Feedler, Experience working with Git version control systems.

Soft skills:

- Attentive to details;
- Analytical skills;
- Customer focus.